Bhawna Agarwal

Product Designer with 6 years of formal design education, and 5+ years of experience designing and shipping well-crafted, high-impact experiences in the industry. I specialize in applying product thinking to break down complex problems and craft helpful experiences.

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Product Designer, Wish

May-August 2020 (Intern), January 2021-Present (Full-time) | San Francisco

- Led design for Wish Local pickup programs. Strategized, designed, and shipped several high-impact projects in a fast-paced, collaborative environment, which made the user experience significantly better.
- Demonstrated initiative by contributing to Wish's design system, and leading design for search filters for the Wish shopping app

UX Designer, Microsoft

April 2018-July 2019, Full-time | Hyderabad, India

- · Sole designer for Microsoft's Azure Backup product (Enterprise software)
- Collaborated with 10+ product managers over multiple projects to deliver experiences for the Azure Backup service
- Owned the design, and delivered end-to-end experiences for Backup Center in close collaboration with PMs, Engineers, and the Azure UX team

UX Designer, Postman API Platform

June 2016-December 2017, Full-time | Bangalore, India

- · Joined as the 21st employee, and reported to the CEO
- Applied extensive product thinking to envision, craft, and ship 6+ core
 projects within one year working as the Design Lead (sole designer). These
 experiences are providing productivity gains to 15 million+ users.
- Pitched a more usable and extensible Data Editor (a core data manipulation component) proposal to executive leadership, got buy-in, and worked extremely closely with a developer to ship the new Data Editor
- Wore multiple hats provided customer support, and wrote product copy and feature marketing blog posts
- Was appreciated by the team for my ability to break down complex problems and conceptualize innovative solutions

Earlier experiences

- UX Designer, Housing.com, Full-time | June-December 2015
- UX Design Intern, HCII, Carnegie Mellon University | May-July 2014
- UX Design Intern, Robert Bosch | May-July 2013

EDUCATION

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor

Masters in Information

IIT Guwahati, India

Bachelor of Design with Minor in Computer Science

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Publications in ACM digital library as first author
- First position in OzCHI 2014 –
 International student design challenge
- · S.N. Bose Scholar

SKILLS

| UX Research | Software |
|----------------------|-------------|
| and Design | Figma |
| Contexual Inquiry | Sketch |
| User Interviews | Principle |
| Persona Building | Invision |
| Writing Job Stories | Photoshop |
| Info. Architecture | Illustrator |
| Heuristic Evaluation | InDesign |
| Usability Testing | Tableau |
| Wireframing | |
| Mobile Design | Coding |
| Visual/UI Design | HTML/ CSS |
| Prototyping | Javascript |
| UX Writing | jQuery |
| Storytelling | Python |

PORTFOLIO

bhawna2109.github.io/